genomeplatform.com 2012-03-13

# Genome, powered by OSM, privacy policy

Genome, powered by OSM ("Genome"), is a technology platform offered by interclick, inc. that leverages interclick's proprietary technology, OSM.

On December 14, 2011, interclick was acquired by Yahoo! and will soon become part of the Yahoo! network of products and services. User information collected by interclick continues to be subject to the interclick Privacy Policy. In the future, you may be asked to link your interclick account information to an existing or new Yahoo! ID. At that point, the Yahoo! Privacy Policy will apply to all information associated with your interclick account.

interclick provides targeted and optimized digital marketing solutions for advertisers. In the course of providing these services, interclick collects and analyzes the online behaviors of consumers across its network of sites. It is critical to interclick that consumers' privacy, rights and choices are maintained during this process.

Accordingly, interclick is committed to following the privacy guideline in accordance with [NAI privacy principles](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/principles.asp).

This Privacy Policy is intended to inform consumers how interclick collects, maintains and processes information we collect in the delivery of our network advertising services.

On the interclick network, we collect non-personally identifiable information (non-PII) such as web sites visited, content viewed, ad interaction, interaction with advertiser websites, search terms used, and other click and browsing behavior. Additionally, we may collect non-PII technical information including IP address, OS type, browser type, and language settings. interclick also purchases anonymous consumer interest data from 3rd party data providers which are associated to web browsers.

interclick neither creates nor uses sensitive data segments to provide its targeted and optimized digital marketing solutions for advertisers. However, we recognize that consumers may have differing opinions regarding which data segments are sensitive. In order to provide transparency around potentially sensitive data segments collected and used by our technology solutions, interclick provides examples of segments within this policy.

For example, we may use health related segments such as  _Interest > Health, Beauty & Personal Care > Health_ (click here for a complete health segment list); or financial segments such as  _In-Market > Financial Products & Services > Credit Products_ (click here for a complete financial segment list).

While we do not use these segments to identify, locate or contact consumers, interclick encourage consumers to contact us for more information about our use of potentially sensitive data segments at [privacy@interclick.com](mailto:privacy@interclick.com). And if you want to view the segments that interclick has stored about your browsing behavior for targeting purposes, click here and scroll to section entitled "My Categories."

Cookies are small packets of data stored on your computer that allow sites to recognize your browser when you revisit the site. Generally, sites use this cookie to provide services such as logging you in automatically on repeat visits, delivering you information, maintaining your shopping cart and understanding how you are interacting with the site. These cookies enable sites to customize the site to your needs and interests, so that they can be as valuable and relevant to you as possible.

Like many websites, interclick sets a cookie on your computer containing an anonymous identifier. This cookie allows interclick to better analyze consumer behavior with the goal of providing more relevant advertising.

You are always free to decline cookies, but by doing so you may not be able to use certain features on the websites or take full advantage of all the website offerings and targeted advertising. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, erase cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set.

You may also click here to opt-out of data collection and targeting cookies from interclick. Please note that if you buy a new computer, upgrade or change Web browsers or delete this "opt out" cookie, you will need to perform this process again.

interclick has created a technology that uses consumer information to create anonymous consumer segments. For example, consumers that demonstrate car buying behaviors are grouped into an auto-buyer segment. These segments will be used to target and optimize advertiser campaigns to consumers who demonstrate that particular behavior. interclick does not use this information to identify, locate or contact consumers.

interclick has created a technology platform called Genome, powered by OSM. Genome is a self-service audience recommendation and planning platform that enables our advertising partners to create anonymous consumer segments (e.g., travel enthusiast) to target and optimize their advertiser campaigns. However, interclick ultimately cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of any of our advertising partners and encourages consumers to read the privacy policies of any website they visit.

We maintain non-PII information on consumer behavior and technical information for 90 days. This data includes web sites visited, content viewed, ad interaction, interaction with advertiser websites, search terms used, and other click and browsing behavior. It also includes non-PII technical information including IP address, OS, browser type, language settings.

We are more than happy to respond to any customer inquiries about privacy concerns. Please contact us at [privacy@interclick.com](mailto:privacy@interclick.com) or at the address below with any questions of complaints.

For more information, about relevant advertising practices, please see the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) web site.

You can opt-out of the targeted advertising delivered by interclick by requesting an "opt-out" cookie (a blank cookie) by interclick, which will prevent information from being uniquely associated with your browser. This allows you to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising from interclick without erasing other cookies associated with your browser.

This opt-out means that interclick will store collect information unique to your browser behavior and will be unable to recognize your browser from one visit to the next. Opting-out does not mean you will not receive online advertising by interclick. However, because interclick is not able to uniquely identify your browser, interclick is unable to deliver ads tailored to your Web preferences and usage patterns.

Please note that if you buy a new computer, upgrade or change Web browsers or delete this "opt out" cookie, you will need to perform this process again.

To see other companies that offer opt outs and to use other tools to manage your opt out choices, please visit the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) opt out page.

interclick reserves the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we decide to change it, we will post a link from our homepage, and possibly other highly visible places we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

_This policy was last updated on December 14, 2011._

* * *

Privacy policy regarding information collected on the interclick website.

interlick only collects personal information on our [website](http://www.interclick.com/) when you make inquiries, and we only use your personal information to contact you regarding that inquiry. Interclick does not store or distribute personal information in any other manner. If we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection we will notify you via email. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. In addition, if we make any material changes in our privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in our database, we will post a prominent notice on our web site notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post the notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

We do not use cookies on the interclick.com website to track your usage in a personally identifiable way. We may use cookies to collect standard information found in a website log file such as IP address, web browser version, etc, but we do not match this information to your personally identifiable information.

We reserve the right to disclose information we have collected from you if required to do so by law, or in the good faith belief that such action is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process, respond to claims, or to protect the rights, property or safety of our company, our employees, customers, or the public.

A link from genomeplatform.com and/or interclick.com to another website does not imply our endorsement of that site. We do not control the sites to which we link and assume no responsibility for their content or privacy policies. Therefore, you should carefully review the privacy policies that apply to any sites you access genomeplatform.com and interclick.com.

If you have any question about our site, company or service, you should first consult our [website](http://www.interclick.com/). This site includes links to company information, answers to frequently asked questions, and all of interclick and Genome's current policies. If you have further questions or any concerns or complaints about how your personal information is used, please contact us at [privacy@interclick.com](mailto:privacy@interclick.com).

If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, email or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, we provide a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can be done by contacting support.

interclick uses industry standard practices to safeguard the confidentiality of your information. interclick treats data as an asset that must be protected against loss and unauthorized access. We employ many different security techniques to protect such data from unauthorized access by users inside and outside the company. Only authorized administrators have password-protected access to our data and we routinely review our security logs and perform regular security audits.

**interclick, inc.**  
11 West 19th Street, 10th floor  
New York, NY 10010  
212.574.4200
